nicholasimorris1993@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced Scientific Programmer with a demonstrated history of working in Computer Software for over 7 years. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science and Master of Engineering in Industrial Engineering from Rochester Institute of Technology.

Experienced Poet with a demonstrated history of creative writing for over 7 years. Strong and sensitive thinker with thousands of words written in various writing structures from my diverse life experiences, and careful reading and listening.

To work for a job where my critical thinking skills can facilitate contemporary solutions. In this job, I will make empirical decisions with the combined understanding of creative thinking, psychology, and philosophy to describe key patterns and anticipate desired outcomes.

Key Strengths

- Machine Learning in Python and R.
- Optimization in Python and AMPL.
- Back-end Programming in Python. Familiar with SQL and Bash.

- Psychological and Philosophical awareness of the human condition.
- Passionate about authenticity,
 Fordism, caretaking, and nobility.
- Secure and silent with the determination to speak assertively yet caringly when necessary.

Education

Undergraduate/Graduate Student

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester NY, Aug-2011 - Nov-2018 (7 yr 4 mo)

- Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering, Aug-2011 to May-2017
- Master of Engineering in Industrial & Systems Engineering, Aug-2015 to May-2017
- Doctor of Philosophy in Engineering, Aug-2017 to Nov-2018

Work Experience

Digital Creator

E-Commerce, Boston MA, Jul 2022 - Present (1 yr 10 mo +)

- Full-stack developer of a machine learning platform.
- Writer and e-commerce merchant of poems and calligraphy products.
- Online life coach.

Data Analytics Engineer

FacilityConneX, Nashua NH, Oct 2020 – Jul 2022 (1 yr 10 mo)

- Back-end developer for continuous performance and reliability monitoring.
- Developed real-time machine learning in Python for a data streaming platform.
- Developed real-time analytics in Python on a data streaming platform.
- Code conversions from C# to Python.
- Developed time series dashboards.

Data Scientist

Aspen Technology, Bedford MA, Mar 2019 – Jun 2020 (1 yr 4 mo)

- Researched and constructed hybrid machine learning with first principles using Python and R.
- Developed the Python back-end engine for Hybrid Model Builder.
- Back-end developer of Python libraries for Hybrid AI Builder.
- Went to the 2020 East Open Data Science Conference to engage with the community.

Researcher (Student)

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester NY, Sep 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 yr 3 mo)

- Presented vaccine research on global distribution optimization for the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation at the 2017 INFORMS conference.
- Using statistics and optimization in R and AMPL, modeled budget uncertainty in the global vaccine market.
- Using machine learning in R, developed a healthcare risk index for each country over time.
- Reviewed vaccine literature using natural language processing in R.

Data Scientist (Intern)

Geisinger Health, Danville PA, Jun 2017 – Aug 2017 (3 mo)

- Using machine learning in R, modeled the likelihood of a patient not donating to the MyCode program that genetically predicts illness and disease.
- Using machine learning in R, modeled the distinguishing characteristics of bladder cancer patients.

Data Analyst (Intern)

Geisinger Health, Danville PA, Jun 2016 – Aug 2016 (3 mo)

- Using statistics in R and Teradata, made recommendations to executives of two neighboring hospitals on how to share their demands based on an analysis of personal health records and doctor schedules.
- Using statistics in Excel and Teradata, made recommendations to the hospital's operations staff on responding to changing occupancy levels based on a time series analysis of personal health records.

Simulation Modeler (Student)

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester NY, Nov 2015 - Mar 2016 (5 mo)

• Using Simio, developed a hierarchical discrete event simulation model of a manufacturing facility for the United States Department of Defense.

Product Management Analyst (Intern)

Mercury Systems, Chelmsford MA, Jun 2015 – Aug 2015 (3 mo)

- Developed a system of Excel spreadsheets to automate the pricing of new products.
- Using machine learning in R, created a model for the price range of new products.

Continuous Improvement Engineer (Intern)

JMA Wireless, Liverpool NY, Jun 2014 – Jan 2015 (8 mo)

- Provided a time series analysis of safety, quality, delivery, and cost for multiple manufacturing cells.
- Ran time studies on multiple manufacturing cells. Designed and machined a system for line balancing the manufacturing cells. And developed an Excel spreadsheet for redesigning the line balancing system.
- Measured the floor layouts of multiple manufacturing cells to redesign inventory and machine locations using AutoCAD and tape.
- Carried out a repeatability and reproducibility analysis on multiple workstations using Excel and Minitab.